ISHAAN AGARWAL

Electrical and Computer Engineering Student

ishaan.agarwal123@yahoo.com (4

(403) 835 2878

https://ishaanag.github.io/PersonalWebsite/

I like to solve problems. As I progress through my career and education, I continue to be faced with challenging topics relating to technology and business. As a problem solver, I strive to reach innovative solutions with the utilization of my professional, personal, and educational experiences. These experiences include a co-op position at Deloitte involving strategic market analysis, personal projects in emerging technologies such as artificial intelligence and big data, and my ongoing engineering education.

KEY SKILLS

Data Analysis

Product Management Trello, Agile, Scrum, UI/UX Design

Market Strategy, Business Intelligence

Software Engineering

Python, C++, C, ARM Assembly, HTML, CSS Python (Numpy), Excel (Pivot, Macros, VBA)

Tableau

Business and Sales Client Service, Technical Sales, Business

Process Improvement, Team Leadership

EXPERIENCE

Client Portfolio Analyst Intern Deloitte

May 2019 - Aug 2019 Calgary, AB

 Collaborated with partners and market-leaders to identify knowledge gaps within the market development strategy for Deloitte Private. Resolved these gaps with the use of data-driven insights including the collection, extraction, and analysis of data. Resulted in a strengthened understanding of relevant direction and actionable focus areas amongst leadership.

Skills Applied: Data Analysis, Market Strategy, Business Intelligence

 Coordinated the project management of client portfolio by performing segmentation analysis for asset management. This involved workflow optimization for data analysis processes including automation of periodic reporting to facilitate quicker turn-around times of key performance indicators to management.
Skills Applied: Project Management, Business Process Improvement

Engineering Intern Exergy Solutions

May 2018 - Aug 2018 Calgary, AB

 Lead development of a 3D printed robot arm which was showcased as the potential of additive manufacturing. Presented at Global Petroleum Show, a multi-vendor sales event in Calgary.

Skills Applied: Python, SolidWorks, 3D Printing, Mechanical Design

 Created a visual presentation for COSIA (an oil sand innovation summit) inspiring industry professionals to use 3D printing technology as a sustainable tool for assisting and accelerating the prototyping process while reducing emissions and waste.

Skills Applied: Brand Marketing, Public Speaking, Graphic Design

PROJECTS & ACHIEVEMENTS

UBC Launchpad: Business Strategist

 As part of largest student-run software engineering team at UBC, led product management of machine learning software solution including strategy, roadmap, and feature definition

RISC Machine

 Developed a Turing complete reduced instruction set computer with 16 operations including arithmetic, read/write memory, and branch instructions

BeatTheStreet Investment Competition

 Won first place in city-wide investment simulation competition with a return of 128.92% resulting in a net worth of \$228,921.05 at the end of the 3-month competition

Alberta Skills Competition Gold Medalist

 Unanimously won gold medal for competition in graphic design out of 17 top-competitors from across Alberta

nwHacks and XdHacks

 Competed in nwHacks, a 24-hour hackathon with 700 competitors and developed an automated grading platfrom using React

EDUCATION

University of British Columbia Bachelor of Applied Science -Electrical Engineering (Co-op Program)

Vancouver, BC 2017 - 2022